# **Justin Cheng**

New York, NY 10029 | https://github.com/jcheng01 | www.linkedin.com/in/chengjustin0222/

A third-year student pursuing a BS in Information Management & Technology with a focus in Front end development Classroom experience in high-demand programming languages along with experience in IT infrastructure.

#### **EDUCATION**

Syracuse University, iSchool for Information Studies – Syracuse, NY

September 2020 - May 2024

Major: Information Management & Technology

**GPA:** 3.68

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6, HTML, CSS/SCSS, JSON, Typescript Frameworks: React, Node.js, Bootstrap, Next.js, Tailwind CSS

Developer Tools: Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, MySQL, Vite, ESlinting

**Concepts:** Scrum/Agile, REST APIs, Design patterns, MVC, Call stack event loop, Linked lists, Array functions, OOP, Object methods, Callbacks/Promises/Async Await, Prototypal Inheritance, Components, DOM manipulation, Mutability

### FRONT END WEB APPLICATIONS

My Webpage V2 | JavaScript, React, SCSS, Next.js

March 2023 - May 2023

 Second iteration of personal website. Fun self-project to work on responsive UI while working with React hooks to handle shared component logic - https://justin-cheng.vercel.app/

Replicated Hangman Game | React, Typescript, Vite, Tailwind CSS

February 2023 – February 2023

• Explored new building tools and deployed using GitHub pages. Practiced how to pass down states through different components in React with Typescript support

**Image Recognition AI page** | *React, SCSS, Tailwind CSS, API, JSON* 

November 2022 – December 2022

 Created single web page using React and Tailwind to fetch JSON resources from two REST APIs. The goal is to demonstrate how an AI can understand a randomly generated image by parsing through outputted information

Pokémon Database | React, Tailwind CSS, API, JSON

September 2022 – October 2022

 Used Pokémon API to create an application using React.js and Tailwind imitating a database. The single page returns respective Pokémon data from API server using entered name to map through arrays of objects

# **RELEVANT COURSEWORK**

- **IST 363** Utilized PHP and custom theming with WordPress. At the end coordinate the application with React, WordPress, and Next.js to customize professional front-end imitation restaurant website
- **IST 466 (current)** Capstone course for Information Management and Technology majors. It is an integration of management strategies, information uses, and information technologies as related to professional conduct, ethics, and career strategies. In-depth review and use of case studies.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Syracuse University - iSchool

Syracuse, NY

Student Technology Consultant

September 2022 – Present

- Collaborate with other IT department staff to resolve inquiries and ensure quality support at a rate of 100%
- Providing technical support over the phone, virtual ticketing, and in person, including configuration of student MS outlook, SU Blackboard, and AirOrangeX
- Trained in iSchool technology help desk resources, policies, and services to provide technical support over the phone and in person, and maintaining the smooth operation of the iSchool facilities

#### Syracuse University - Barnes Center

Syracuse, NY

Front Desk Receptionist

September 2020 – December 2021

- Provided excellent patron service, effectively maintaining a 99% satisfaction rate
- Answered Queries on wide-ranging service concerns utilizing facility virtual catalog